Panagiotis Simakis

Curriculum Vitae

Athens, 115 27, Greece

Summary

Software Engineer with more than 5 years of working experience in the field of Software Development, Data Science, Data Engineering & MLOps. Has worked in various sectors from Digital Marketing to e-Commerce. Loves to work with Modern Data Stacks and to productize Machine Learning Systems. He usually contributes to FOSS projects during the nights.

EXPERIENCE

Netdata

Senior Data Engineer

Oct. 2021 - Present

Development and maintenance of ETL pipelines for BI purposes using Apache Airflow, Cloud Functions and BigQuery. Implementation of Data Lineages using Datahub.

Technologies: GCP, BigQuery, Cloud Functions, Apache Airflow, Datahub, Github, Docker

Convert Group

Athens, Greece

Athens, Greece

Data Engineer

May 2020 - Sep. 2021

Development of ETL pipelines and data automation pipelines. Productize the internal Machine Learning services. Contribute on back-end development of eRetail Content platform.

Technologies: Prefect, AWS, Django/REST, Docker, PostgreSQL, Amazon Redshift, Celery, MLflow

XPLAIN

Data Scientist Feb. 2017 - Apr. 2020

Data and Text Mining using state-of-the-art and disruptive methods. Design and development of distributed web crawlers. Database administration and optimization. Implementation of workflow pipelines. Deployment of ML models to production as RESTfull API services.

Technologies: Python, MySQL, Celery, Docker Swarm, ELK, spaCy, NumPy/pandas

Sociality Athens, Greece

Junior Web Developer - Intern

Feb. 2016 - June 2016

Web development using WordPress. Implementation of WordPress plugins for Woocommerce. Development of custom functionalities for WordPress.

Technologies: WordPress, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Shell, SQL, PHP
- Databases & Data Warehouses: MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack, BigQuery
- Data & ML Workflow Platforms: Prefect, MLflow, Apache Airflow
- Data Science & NLP: pandas/NumPy, scikit-learn, Keras, spaCy
- Web Scraping: lxml, Selenium, Scrapy, Beautiful Soup
- Web Frameworks: Django/REST, FastAPI
- Version Control Systems & Platforms: Git, Github, Bitbucket
- Cloud Computing: AWS, GCP

EDUCATION

Department of Computer Engineering & Informatics, University of Patras

Patras, Greece

Diploma (equivalent to B.Eng + M.Eng); GPA: 6.87

Sep. 2010 - Feb. 2017

Thesis: Design and Implementation of a Methodology for the Automatic Identification of the User Geographic Idiom in a Social Media Text Corpus. supervisor: Megalooikonomou Vasileios, grade: 10/10

Languages

• Greek: Native		
• English: Proficient	Certificate of Proficiency in English, Th	he University of Mishigan
• French: Elementary		$Delf\ A2$
CERTIFICATIONS & CONFERENCES		
Astronomer Certification for Apache Airflow	Fundamentals: Astronomer link	Apr. 2022
• Apache Pulsar Fundamentals: StreamNative link		Jan. 2022
• Open Source Software Development, Linux and Git Specialization: Coursera link		Jan. 2022
• Architecting with Google Kubernetes Engine Specialization: Coursera link		Dec. 2021
• AWS Fundamentals Specialization: Coursera link		Nov. 2020
• $O\pi e \setminus n$ conference: Athens, Greece link		Mar. 2019
• 4th & 10th Conference of FOSS: Patras, Athens the full list	s, Greece	2011, 2017

PUBLICATIONS

- Simaki, V., Simakis, P., Paradis, C., & Kerren, A. (2018). Detection of StanceRelated Characteristics in Social Media Text. In SETN '18: 10th Hellenic Conference on Artificial Intelligence New York: Association for Computing Machinery, Inc. DOI: 10.1145/3200947.3201017
- Simaki, V., Simakis, P., Paradis, C, & Kerren, A. (2017). Identifying the Authors' National Variety of English in Social Media Text. In Proceedings of RANLP 2017 Recent Advances in Natural Language, ACL Anthology (in press)

Interests

GNU/Linux, MLOps, NLP, F/OSS

ACTIVITIES

Photography, Traveling, Hiking, Sailing